（芝加哥）
妈妈生病了 就这么突然发生了
Mummy got sick. It happened just like that.
没人可以帮上忙
Nobody could stop it.
这不公平，没有什么原因
It isn't fair. There's no reason.
再不停问原因，只会令人发疯
And if we start asking why, we'll go crazy.
只要放进任何一个微波炉 五分钟就可以了
Five minutes in the microwave. Any one of them.
你知道怎样弄果汁吗？
Do you know how to make juice?
放进微波炉五分钟
Microwave. Five minutes.
给，这是我的心理医生 给他打个电话吧
Here. It's my shrink. Call him.
这是丧偶互助会
Loss of Spouse Support Group.
芝加哥癌症病人家属支援会 父母失去另一半的
Chicago Cancer Family Network. Parents without Partners.
拥抱自己，拥抱朋友 拥抱一位心理医生
"Hug Yourself", "Hug a Friend", "Hug a Shrink"...
努力工作，工作能拯救你 唯有工作能帮你度过这状况
Work hard, that'll save you. Only work will see you through this.
别介意 一位刚失去妻子的男人就会这样
Don't mind him, he's just a guy who's lost his wife.
我想我真正需要的是改变
What I think we really need is... change.
好主意，放几周假，跟乔纳去钓个鱼
Good idea. Take a few weeks off, take Jonah fishing.
不，是真的改变，新城市
No, real change. A new city.
一个新地方 让我不再想起玛吉的地方
Some place where I don't think of Maggie at every corner.
（瑞格里球场 芝加哥《小熊队》球场）
你要去哪？
Where are you gonna go?
我在考虑去西雅图
I was thinking about Seattle.
过几个月，你会再和女人约会 你会遇到心仪的对象的
In a few months, you'll be seeing women. You'll meet someone.
对，向前看，这正是我想做的 几个月后，我会复原，重新长个心
Move on, fine, that's what I'll do. I'll just grow a new heart.
-山姆，对不起，我不是这意思 -我知道，只是有些事情一生一次足矣
- Sam, I'm sorry, I didn't mean... - I know. But it can't happen twice.
?Jimmy Dante: "As Time Goes By"?
?You must remember this, ?
?A kiss is still a kiss ?
?A sigh is just a sigh ?
?The fundamental things apply ?
?As time goes by ?
?And when two lovers woo ?
?They still say "I love you" ?
?On that you can rely ?
?No matter what the future brings ?
?As time goes by ?
?Moonlight and love songs ?
?Never out of date ?
?Hearts full of passion ?
?Jealousy and hate ?
?Woman needs man ?
?And man must have his mate ?
?That no one can deny ?
?It's still the same old story ?
?A fight for love and glory ?
?A case of do or die ?
?The world ?
?Will always welcome lovers ?
?As time goes by ?
（巴尔的摩 18个月后）
-红发的高女人是你的表姐艾琳 -一脸失望那个就是她
- The tall redhead is cousin Irene.  - You'll see her disappointed look.
-哈洛则是跟女秘书有染 -直到艾琳的狗病死
- Harold ran off with the secretary. - Until Irene had the dog put down.
你的哥哥丹尼斯是教授 在约翰斯·霍普金斯
Your brother Dennis is professor at Johns Hopkins.
-她老婆是…贝琪 -世上最难缠的人
- He's married to... Betsy. - The most competitive woman ever.
-我怎能记住那么多事情呢？ -华特，你可以的
- How will I remember all this? - Walter, you will!
-你的米顿叔叔赔掉所有钱 -还有其他人的钱
- Uncle Milton lost all his money... - And some other people's.
因为骗局，更别提国税局或监狱
...in a pyramid scheme. Don't mention the IRS or the prisons.
你妈叫芭芭拉 你爸是克里夫
Your mother's Barbara, your father's Cliff...
-我爸收集电动火车 -真的？
- He has electric trains. - Really?
我算乘龙快婿吗？
Am I what they had in mind?
华特，他们会喜欢你的
Walter, they're gonna love you!
大家注意！ 安妮有事要宣布
Everybody, Annie has an announcement.
华特和我订婚了
Walter and I are engaged.
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
恭喜了，华特
Congratulations, Walter.
上帝保佑你
Bless you!
-你还好吧？ -大概是花
- Are you all right? - Maybe it's the flowers.
-那把花移开 -不，我要打喷嚏了
- We'll move them. - No! I feel terrible, sneezing now.
-偏偏这时候打喷嚏 -他对什么都过敏
- This is a very important moment. - He's allergic to everything.
我对蜜蜂过敏
Bees. I'm allergic to bees.
不管哪种蜜蜂 我们随身携带肾上腺素
He's allergic to all bees. We have to take adrenalin with us.
-吃一颗小果仁 -我的脑袋就会肿胀，然后会昏过去
- If he eats just a bit of a nut... - My head swells, and I drop dead.
-哈洛碰到蜜蜂也一样 -我和你妈结婚时吃鲑鱼
- It's the same with him and bees. - We had salmon at our wedding.
-那可是婚礼的必备佳肴 -我对鲑鱼不会过敏
- A wedding without salmon is... - I'm not allergic to salmon.
但是也难讲
But you never know.
-没错 -哈洛不是每次都对蜜蜂过敏
- You never know. - He wasn't always allergic to bees.
-我们开香槟是为了庆祝什么？ -庆祝米顿叔叔假释
- What did we do with our champagne? - Uncle Milton's parole.
-安妮，你什么时候结婚？ -六月初，在花园举行
- When are you getting married? - Early June, in the garden.
-哈洛和蜜蜂怎么办？ -我对蜜蜂过敏
- What about Harold and bees? - I'm allergic to bees.
冷鲜鱼、黄瓜沙拉、草莓
Cold salmon, cucumber salad, strawberries.
我对草莓过敏
I'm afraid I am allergic to strawberries.
你没关系吗？
Is this all right with you?
今天我是全世界 最幸运的人
I'm the luckiest man-man-man on the face of the earth-earth-earth.
-陆·葛瑞的台词是… -《Pride of the Yankees》…
- That's Lou Gehrig's line from... - Pride of the Yankees.
-《Pride of the Yankees》里头的 -棒球电影，这句话很经典
- Pride of the Yankees! - Baseball. An historical reference.
我提议举杯贺喜 敬我妹妹
I would like to propose a toast. To my kid sister!
敬华特和我的宝贝
To Walter and my baby.
大家快吃，菜都凉了
Please eat, before it gets cold.
找到了，历史学会想要 我都不肯给
Here it is. I wouldn't give it to the Historical Society.
-哦，妈！ -我知道这款式又在流行了
- Oh, Mum... - These things are back in fashion.
外婆的结婚礼服
Grandmother's dress.
-他人不错 -我知道，他很棒吧？
- He's a lovely man, Annie. - He is, isn't he?
而且是优秀运动员 我们要去华盛顿特区见他的父母
And he's a wonderful athlete. We're going to DC to see his parents.
-你们怎么认识的？ -说来可笑
- How did it happen? - It's silly, really.
我们在公司见过 他是出版商代表
I'd seen him at the office. He's the associate publisher.
有一天我们刚巧 向同一家店订三明治
We had both ordered sandwiches...
他拿到我那会令他过敏的 生菜番茄全麦包
...and he got my tomato on wheat, which he's allergic to.
我拿到他的生菜番茄白面包 太神奇了，对吗？
And I got his tomato on white. Amazing, isn't it?
每天做多少决定 随便一个便能改变你的一生
You make a million decisions, and a sandwich changes your life.
命中注定
Destiny takes a hand.
我们不能接受不如意的事情发生 所以才发明命运
We invented destiny, because we don't want things to be accidental.
但你怎解释你们叫了 几乎同样的东西，除了面包外？
Then why did you order the same sandwich except for the bread?
有多少人只吃生菜番茄三明治 连点肉都不加？
How many people like tomato without something else, like tuna?
这不是预兆，纯属巧合
It wasn't a sign. It was a coincidence.
我和家人到大西洋城 你爸在那当侍者
I was in Atlantic City, where Cliff was a waiter.
他当晚恰好与人调班
He wasn't supposed to work that night. What if he hadn't?
他请我到码头来午夜漫步 我说过上千次了，不过我才不管
He asked me to take a midnight walk. I told you this a million times.
他握着我的手 我看着，分不出谁是谁的手指
He held my hand. I looked down and couldn't tell our fingers apart.
-我心里便明白了 -什么？
- And I knew. - What?
-什么？ -魔力，是魔力
- What? - It was magic.
这就是魔力
Magic.
我知道我们将终生幸福厮守 就像你对华特一样
I knew we'd be together forever. Just like you and Walter.
华特，挺正式的名字
Walter. It's quite a formal name.
我还知道我和你爸…
I knew that your father and I would have a wonderful time in...
在床上会很合的来 你们是这么叫的吧
...the sack, I believe you call it.
是过了几年才水乳交融
It took years before it worked like clockwork. It takes time.
-我们已经… -没关系，感觉如何？
- We already... - Fine, fine. How's it working?
-水乳交融 -喔，亲爱的
- Like clockwork. - Oh, honey...
-这是预兆 -你又不信
- It's a sign. - You don't believe in signs.
他们很喜欢你，如我所料
They loved you. I told you they would.
-我爱你 -我爱你，华特
- I love you. - I love you, Walter.
-你有小名吗？ -没有
Did anyone ever call you anything other than Walter?
-小时候也没有？ -没有
- Not even when you were young? - Not even when I was young.
-确定不搭我的车回去吗？ -我周五怎么回巴尔的摩？
- Don't you want to drive with me? - Then I can't get back on Friday.
我把送你继母的礼忘在屋里了 等我们老了
I forgot your stepmother's present. When we're old and gray...
你得提醒我戴假牙 这样我出门就不会忘了
...you must remind me to put my teeth in, so I don't go out without them.
-我等你 -等我，好
- I'll wait. - You'll wait? Oh, right.
别等了，你先走吧 我就比你晚10分钟
No, go ahead. We're late anyway. I'll be ten minutes behind you.
?"Sleigh Ride"?
?Sleigh bells jingle-ing ?
?Ring ting tingle-ing too ?
?Horses, horses, horses ?
?It's lovely weather ?
?For a sleigh ride together with you ?
?Giddy-up, giddy-up ?
（华盛顿）
?The snow is falling ?
?And friends are calling "Yoo Hoo" ?
?Friends are calling "Yoo Hoo" ?
?Ding-a-ling-a-ling ?
?Sleigh ride together with you ?
?Horse, horses, horses ?
?Horse, horses ?
?Rogers and Dale Evans: "Jingle Bells"
?Jingle bells, jingle bells ?
?Jingle all the way ?
?Oh, what fun, it is to ride ?
?In a one horse open sleigh, hey ?
?Jingle bells ?
欢迎收听“感情世界”
Welcome to "You and Emotions."
我是玛莎·菲尔斯通医生 由芝加哥向全美播送
I'm Dr. Marcia Fieldstone, broadcasting live from Chicago.
今晚我们谈愿望与梦想 你这个圣诞节有何愿望？
Tonight we'll talk about wishes. What's your wish this Christmas?
有何愿望？ 我的愿望是转台
My wish is to change the station.
-医生与你的主题是“你的脾脏” -下辈子吧
- And now: "You and your spleen." - Not on your life.
接下来“圣诞铃声”倒着唱 由新泽西合唱团呈献
Coming up, "Jingle Bells" backwards, sung by...
-西雅图，说吧 -我叫乔纳…
- Seattle, go ahead. - This is Jonah...
不用说姓氏 你的声音很年轻，几岁了？
No last names, Jonah. How old are you?
-八岁 -怎么这么晚还没睡？
- I'm eight. - You're up late.
-在西雅图不晚 -对，你的圣诞愿望是什么？
- It's not so late in Seattle. - You're right. What's your wish?
-不为我，是为我爸，他需要新妻子 -你不喜欢现在这个？
- My dad needs a new wife. - You don't like the one he has?
-问题是他没有！ -你妈呢？
- He doesn't have one. - Where's your mum?
-她死了 -谁会相信有这种事
- She died. - Well, who can believe this?
-我很难过，但我爸比我还糟 -你和他谈过吗？
- I've been sad, but Dad's worse. - Have you talked to him about it?
没有，这会让他更伤心
No, that makes him sadder.
我了解，乔纳 你爸现在在家吗？
Jonah, is your dad home?
-在忙吗？ -不忙，他在甲板上
- Is he busy? - No, he's out on the deck.
我可以帮忙 但要他听电话
Can't you ask him to talk to me?
-坏女人！挂上，乔纳，别听她的 -不行，他会杀了我
- Wretched woman! Hang up, Jonah! - No, he'd kill me.
相信我，乔纳，他知道你关心 他就不会生气
He won't be angry when he hears how concerned you are about him.
-打赌？ -如果他骂人，就再不听你的节目
- Want to bet? - If he yells, you lose a fan.
爸，有人打电话找你
Dad, there's someone on the phone for you.
他叫山姆
His name is Sam.
山姆，假如你刚开收音机 今晚的主题是你的愿望与梦想
If you've just tuned in, tonight's topic is wishes and dreams.
我们与西雅图通话中
We have a listener from Seattle.
喂？山姆 我是全美电台的菲尔斯通医生
Sam, this is Dr. Fieldstone on Network America.
你想卖什么？ 烤肉架还是刀
What are you selling? Micro-hibachis or knives?
我不卖东西，我想帮你 你儿子来电
Neither. I want to help. Your son asked me for advice.
-问如何帮你找个新妻子 -你是哪位？
- He wants to find you a new wife. - Who is this?
我是全美电台 玛莎·菲尔斯通医生，我们正在广播
Dr. Fieldstone of Network America. You are on the air.
-你打给电台？ -山姆，你在听吗？
- You called a radio station? - Sam, are you there?
-听见 -你儿子觉得你丧妻后郁郁寡欢
- Yes. - You mourn your wife's death.
他非常担心你
Your son is worried about you.
嘿！出来！ 别想叫我一个人出丑
Get out here. I won't go through this alone.
我想他很难向你启齿
It's hard for him to talk to you about this.
我们谈谈 或许能让乔纳宽心一些
If we talk about it, maybe Jonah will feel better.
-跟她谈，她是医生 -什么医生？也许她名字就叫“医生”
- Talk to her. She's a doctor. - Her first name could be Doctor.
-求求你 -山姆，这是他的圣诞愿望
- Please. - Sam, it's his Christmas wish.
-好吧 -很好
- Okay. - Good.
我知道你不想提 您太太去世多久了？
I know this is difficult. When did your wife die?
-大约一年半 -之后你交过女友吗？
- About a year and a half ago. - Have you had any relationships?
-没有 -为什么不？
- No. - Why not?
-玛莎…还是菲尔斯通医生？ -玛莎医生
- Marcia... or Dr. Fieldstone? - Dr. Marcia.
-玛莎医生，我不想无礼 -我也不想探人隐私
- I don't mean to be rude... - I don't want to pry...
-你当然想 -说吧，我在听
- Sure you do. - Go on, Sam. I'm listening.
起先我们父子很痛苦
We had a pretty tough time at first.
但我们还在熬
But we're dealing with it.
我和乔纳会恢复平静 等我摔了他的收音机后
Jonah and I will get along fine, as soon as I break his radio.
我确信你是个好爸爸
I'm sure you're a wonderful father.
-声音听得出来 -当然了
- You can tell a lot from a voice. - Yes, you can.
但乔纳觉得你还在低潮
But Jonah still feels that you're under a cloud.
-你晚上睡得着吗？ -他根本没睡
- Are you sleeping at night? - He doesn't sleep at all.
-你怎么知道？ -我住在这儿，爸爸
- How do you know that? - I live here, Dad.
听着，圣诞节到了
Look, it's Christmas.
玛吉…是我太太…
Maggie... my wife.
她热烈庆祝…
She really did it...
她钟爱… 一切都布置的很美
She loved... She made everything beautiful.
每到这时节更难熬
It's tough this time of year.
-每个孩子都需要妈妈 -你是否也和乔纳一样需要个伴？
- Every kid needs a mother. - Maybe you need someone too.
-是的 -先别回答，广告时间
- Yes. - We'll resume after these messages.
山姆、乔纳，别走开 我们和“西雅图夜未眠”通话
Sam and Jonah, don't go away. I'm talking to Sleepless in Seattle.
等一下来听众反应
We'll be back with listener response.
-那是什么意思？ -别人可以打电话骂你
- What's that? - People call in and dump on you.
有意思，真有用
This is really fun. And helpful.
（首都餐厅 来吃吧）
-他一定是高大翘屁股 -我说他几周不洗澡
- I bet he's tall with a cute butt. - I bet he hasn't bathed in weeks.
-需要什么吗？ -茶，外带
- Yes? - Tea, with the bag out.
-也许我会赶去西雅图送他个新年贺礼 -去呀，千万别开他冰箱
- Maybe I'll just go up to Seattle. - Don't open his refrigerator.
男人都不会把东西包好放入冰箱
Men don't cover food, and they leave it in there till it walks out.
我不会为小事把他踢下床 你明白吗？谢谢你，6角5分
I wouldn't kick him out of bed for eating crackers. Sixty five cents.
这通电话之后便回到“夜未眠” 田纳西纳维市，请说
We'll take a call before we talk to Sleepless. Go ahead, Tennessee.
我想知道他的住址
I'd like to have his address.
甜心，排队吧
Honey, get in line.
-我想问个问题 -问吧
- If I could ask you a question... - Go ahead.
真爱过的人很难再恋爱
People who truly loved are likely to love again.
山姆，你能再如此深爱一个人吗？
Sam, could you love anybody as much as you loved your wife?
玛莎医生，这很难想像
Well, that's hard to imagine.
你打算怎么办？
What are you going to do?
我打算每天清晨起床 整天呼吸
Get out of bed every morning and breathe in and out all day long.
过阵子… 我就不必提醒自己起床呼吸
And after a while I won't have to remind myself to do it.
再过一阵子…我就不会 想起过去的日子有多么完美
And then after a while I won't remember how perfect things were.
您太太的魅力何在？
Why was your wife so special?
你的节目有多长？
How long is your program?
无数件小事情，若加起来
It was a million little things.
那表示我们是前生注定的
When you added them up, it meant we were meant for each other.
我知道 第一次接触她时我便知道
I knew it the very first time I touched her.
就像回家 却是前所未知的家
It was like coming home, only to no home I'd ever known.
而我只是牵她的手…
I was just taking her hand...
扶她下车 我就知道了
...to help her out of a car. And I knew it.
-就像是…魔力 -魔力
- It was like... magic. - Magic.
各位，时间到了 我是芝加哥的菲尔斯通医生
It's time to wrap it up. I'm Dr. Marcia Fieldstone.
祝所有听众有个 神奇的圣诞夜
To all my listeners, a magical and Merry Christmas.
还有你“西雅图夜未眠” 希望再听到你的进展
And Sleepless in Seattle, call and tell us how it's going.
一言为定
You can count on it.
?Ray Charles: "Over The Rainbow"?
?I know ?
?Somewhere over the rainbow ?
?The blue birds fly ?
?Birds fly ?
?Over the rainbow ?
?Why then, oh why can't I? ?
（巴尔的摩太阳报）
他的汤是最鲜美的 而人却是美国最坏的
He sells the best soup ever and he is the meanest man in America.
-很有写头，不止是汤 -写吧
- I feel strongly about this. - Do it.
别叫我采访纽约除夕夜
New Year's Eve. I won't write it.
听着 “芝加哥电信中断两小时
Listen: "Phone service was tied up Christmas Eve...
因一名儿童向电台诉说 其父需要再婚
...when a kid called the radio and said his dad needs a new wife."
两千名妇女 来电索取电话号码”
Two thousand women wanted his number.
我有听到，他说
I heard it. This kid calls up...
我爸爸需要个妻子 主持人要当事人跟她谈
...and the shrink forces the father to talk about it.
他说不，但接着他说出…
Suddenly he starts talking...
他有多爱他老婆 像密西根那些母牛
...about how he fell in love with her like these cows in Michigan.
新闻播过母牛被电流击中 也许是在威斯康星
The cows that got zapped by stray voltage. Maybe it was Wisconsin.
我听着听着… 就开始哭了
Anyway, I was listening to him, and suddenly I was crying.
就像看到电话公司广告
Like when I see the ad...
那女人送她妈 冰箱那一幕
...where the daughter gives her mum the refrigerator with a red bow.
-还有两个孩子在派对 -替爷爷做相册的广告
- Or the two kids at the party. - Making an album for Grandfather!
看了就感动
That kills me!
-你该写一篇相关报导 -写什么？
Write about it. Whatever it is.
告诉你写什么 两千个女人寻夫
Two thousand women calling for a husband?
多少女人渴望爱情啊
Women are desperate for love.
-尤其过了某个年龄 -过四十想嫁真的很难
- Especially over a certain age. - It's hard to get married over 40.
-这项数据不正确 -没错，但听来正确
- That statistic is not true. - But it feels true.
-因为那是事实 -有专书驳斥指出那不正确
- It's true. - A new book proves it isn't true.
-你看过那本书没？ -谁会读那种书啊
- Did you read that book? - Did anybody read that book?
你俩有完没完？ 讲到哪了？
Are you done? Where were we?
若有人丧妻 为何称他鳏夫？而不直接称丧妻人
If someone's a widower, why is he widowed and not widowered?
随便想想
Just wondering.
怎么回事？ 你怎么搞的？
What was that about up there? What's with you?
-没事 -你心里有事，可以告诉我
- Nothing. - There's something. Tell me.
-“西雅图夜未眠”？ -因为他失眠才这么叫他！
- Sleepless in Seattle? - That's what she called him.
现在两千个女人要他的电话 他也许磕药…
Now 2,000 women want his number. He could be a crackhead...
或是性变态、瘾君子 或非常有毛病，像我男友瑞克
...a transvestite, a junkie, or really sick, like my Rick.
他听起来蛮温和的
Actually, he sounded nice.
是吗？原来如此
Really? Now we're getting down to it.
拜托，我正与华特狂恋中 那天晚上他好疯，是什么呢？
I'm madly in love with Walter. He did a crazy thing the other night.
我们笑翻了，什么事呢？
It was so funny. What was that?
我要到波士顿开会
I've got to go to Boston for the convention.
再到温斯顿休公司一趟
And I have to visit Winston-Hughes.
我们何不在情人节周末 在纽约见
Why don't we meet in New York for Valentine's Day weekend?
-好呀，华特 -我们住广场大饭店
- Walter, I'd love to! - We can stay at the Plaza.
-到中央公园溜冰 -注册
- Ice skate in Central Park. - Register.
买餐具银器
You know... for dishes, glasses, silver, everything.
好不好？
How about it?
-我带你去唐人街饮茶 -是麦子做的吗？
- We'll have dim sum in Chinatown. - Is there wheat in it?
应该不是吧
I don't think so.
?Dim sum, dim sum ?
?Dooby-doo-bop ?
10，9，8，7，6…
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six...
5，4，3，2，1！
...five, four, three, two, one...
乔纳，醒醒 球要掉下来了
Jonah, wake up. The ball's dropping.
-新年快乐 -新年快乐
- Happy New Year. - Happy New Year.
-亲霍华德 -晚安，霍华德
- Kiss Howard. - Goodnight, Howard.
?Nat King Cole: "Stardust"?
?Sometimes I wonder ?
?Why I spend ?
?The lonely nights ?
?Dreaming of a song ?
?The melody ?
?Haunts my reverie ?
?And I am once again with you ?
?When our love was new ?
?And each kiss an inspiration ?
?But that was long ago ?
?wow my consolation ?
?Is in the stardust of a song ?
?Beside a garden wall ?
?When stars are bright ?
?You are in my arms ?
?The nightingale ?
?Tells his fairy tale ?
?Of paradise where roses grew ?
我可以喝一半啤酒吗？
Can I have half your beer?
喝吧
Go ahead.
-我以前都怎么说？ -“看着你
What did I use to say? "Here's looking at you"?
-敬你的眼神” -敬我们
- "Here's mud in your eye"? - "Here's to us."
你以前都说“敬我们”
You used to say: "Here's to us."
宝贝，我想你想到心痛
Oh, babe. I miss you so much it hurts.
你说？我说好了
You want to tell him? I'll tell him.
他回来了，他又有新点子
She's back with another idea.
山姆，好高兴碰到你 我听到你上电台，我通告全天下了
Sam, I'm glad you're here. I heard you on the radio. I told everyone.
-我们已经知道了，葛莉丝 -等于昭告全西雅图
- We already knew. From Grace. - Then all of Seattle knows.
当时我正在刷牙，听到你的声音 马上打给我住在赌城的妈
I was brushing my teeth and there you were. I called my mother.
叫她打开收音机 那可是我的建筑师
I said, "Turn on the radio. That's my architect."
你知道吗 男人肯流露真情，那很感人
You know, it's so nice when a man can express his feelings.
-我就做不到 -克莱尔，设计有什么问题？
- I wish I could. - Claire, is there a problem?
我昨晚失眠 你知道那滋味
I couldn't sleep last night. You know what that's like.
因为冰箱放不下盘子
My platters won't fit in the refrigerator.
我一向用盘子盛点心待客 我就换了个冰箱
At parties I use platters, so I want a Sub Zero refrigerator instead.
-入墙架子得重订 -得嵌进壁里
- We have to redo the cabinets. - We'll be into this wall.
-那是主墙 -已经拖了五，六…
- A bearing wall. - That's a delay of five, six...
-十二周 -我不管，做好才重要
...12 weeks. - It's important to get it right.
我和设计师还有约 再见
Well, la decorateur calls. Bye.
这是命吧，她离婚了 我们不想重做，你少个老婆
It's fate. She's divorced, we don't want to do this and you need a wife.
-当不好的事交错发生应怎么形容？ -百慕大三角洲
- Everything intersects. - The Bermuda Triangle.
又一袋，有地方放吗？
Here's one more. Do you have room?
-爸，你看，都是你的 -都在这里
- Dad, they're all for you. - Here you go.
“西雅图夜未眠”
"Sleepless in Seattle."
睡不着就低头喝水
If you can't sleep, try drinking a glass of water from the other side.
我知道怎样治打隔 含一匙糖可以止隔
That's for hiccups. Or you can hold a spoonful of sugar in your mouth.
谢谢
Thank you.
-你为何把地址告诉电台？ -他们打来问呀
- But why give them our address? - They called and asked for it.
“亲爱的西雅图夜未眠 你是我听过最吸引人的男人”
"Dear Sleepless in Seattle. You are the most attractive man I've heard."
他们打来？ 他们怎会知道电话号码？
They called? You gave them our number too?
必须得给，不给不能上节目
You have to, to get on the air.
“亲爱的夜未眠 我住托沙”那在哪？
"Dear Sleepless in Seattle. I live in Tulsa." Where's that?
-俄克拉荷马州，你知道是哪里吗？ -在中部某地方？
- In Oklahoma. Where is that? - Somewhere in the middle.
你在学校上些什么呀？
I won't think about what they don't teach you at school.
不住附近的人都刷掉
I think we should rule out anyone who doesn't live near here.
反正她愿意搭飞机来
She's willing to fly anywhere.
她像我三年级时老师 等一下，她真的是我的小学老师
Looks like my third-grade teacher. She is my third-grade teacher!
-这些你不看吗？ -不看，哪有这样搞的
- Don't you want to read these? - No, it's not how it's done.
我宁愿看自己喜欢的人
I'd rather see somebody I like.
-感觉一下，请她喝一杯 -或吃片比萨
- Then I'd ask her out for a drink. - Or a slice of pizza.
第一次约会不吃饭 免得吃到一半后悔
No dinner on the first date, because halfway through you could regret it.
喝杯酒的话，喜欢再请她吃饭
But if you like them after a drink, you can always ask them to dinner.
不喜欢的话，走人就是了
If not, you can say, "That was great," and go home.
不知这是否不流行了
You see? I wonder if it still works this way.
-不了，是她们追你 -我也刚发现了
- It doesn't. They ask you. - I'm starting to notice that.
你娶新太太 就要有性关系
If you get a new wife, you'll have sex with her, huh?
-希望会 -她会抓你的背吗？
- I certainly hope so. - Will she scratch up your back?
电影里女人 都抓男人的背尖叫
In movies women always scratch the man's back and scream during sex.
-你怎么知道的？ -杰德家有有线电视
- How do you know this? - Jed's got cable.
毛巾递给我
Hand me that towel, please.
谢谢，我帮你擦 杰德家有有线电视
Thank you. Let me get you. "Jed's got cable!"
?Dr. John: "Makin' Whoopee"?
?Another bride ?
?Another groom ?
?Another sunny honeymoon ?
?Another season, another reason ?
?For makin' whoopee ?
?Carly Simon: "In the Wee Small Hours of the Morning"
?When the sun is high ?
?In the afternoon sky ?
?You can always find ?
?Something to do ?
?But from dusk till dawn ?
?As the clock ticks on ?
?Something happens to you ?
?In the wee small hours ?
?Of the morning ?
?While the whole wide world ?
?Is fast asleep ?
?You lie awake ?
?And think about the boy ?
?And never ever think ?
?Of counting sheep ?
现在回到玛莎·菲尔斯通医生 您的心理医生和知心朋友
Now to Dr. Fieldstone, psychologist and the friend you never had.
-记得迈阿密的困惑吗？ -他不再爱我
- Remember Marooned in Miami? - He doesn't love me anymore.
-为何留恋一个不爱你的人？ -丹佛失望者
- Then why stay with him? - Disappointed in Denver.
每次我快到高潮时 他就去做三明治
When I come close to orgasm, he goes to make a sandwich.
-何不先替他做好？ -西雅图夜未眠
- Make a sandwich beforehand. - Sleepless in Seattle.
我打算每天清晨起床 整天呼吸
I'll get up every morning and breathe in and out all day long.
过阵子… 我就不必提醒自己
After a while I won't have to remind myself...
起床，呼吸
...to get up and breathe in and out.
再过一阵子我就不会…
Then after a while I won't have to think about...
想起过去的日子有多么完美
...how I had it great and perfect for a while.
您太太的魅力何在？
Why was your wife so special?
你的节目有多长？
How long is your program?
无数件小事情
It was a million little things.
若加起来 那表示我们是前生注定的
When you added them up, it meant we were meant for each other.
我知道 头一次接触她时我便知道
I knew it, the first time I touched her.
就像回家 却是前所未知的家
It was like coming home, only to no home I'd ever known.
而我只是牵她的手 扶她下车
I was just taking her hand to help her out of a car.
我就知道了 就像是…
And I knew it. It was like...
魔力
...magic.
我快疯了，丹尼斯 你婚姻幸福吗？
I think I'm going crazy, Dennis. Are you happily married?
你为何结婚？ 你们热情难熄？
Why did you get married? Was it trumpets and fireworks?
贝琪说要不就分手，要不就结婚 所以我们就结婚了
Betsy said we had to break up or get married. That's why.
你们邂逅时 你心中只有她吗？
When you met, did you think she was the only one for you?
像是命中注定要结合
That in some way it was fated?
安妮，两情相悦只是
Annie, attraction is...
潜意识互相吸引
...when your subconscious is attracted to their subconscious.
命运只是两条 完全吻合的神经
Fate is two neuroses knowing they're a perfect match.
我根本不认识他 我对一个住在西雅图
I'm having all these fantasies about a man I never even met!
-素不相识的人产生幻想 -西雅图一年下九个月雨
- And he lives in Seattle! - It rains nine months a year there.
我知道，我不想搬去
I know. I won't move to Seattle.
但我不想 有所为不为而遗憾终生
But I don't want to end up wondering what might have happened.
你认为呢？ 是婚前不安，是吗？
What do you think? It's cold feet, isn't it?
-每个人婚前都会紧张，你呢？ -我也是
- Everybody panics. Didn't you? - Yes, I did.
谢谢，说出来我舒服多了
Thanks, Dennis. I feel better now.
珊蒂有个女友练举重的 但她的脖子没有很粗
Sandy's friend is a weightlifter, but her neck isn't that big.
不不，我不是要你替我作媒 只是想搞清楚状况
No, don't set me up. I want to know what it's like out there.
现在的女人找有胸肌 和翘屁股的男人
Women are looking for pecs and a cute butt.
像…“他的屁股好正点” 最近在哪听过？
"He has the cutest butt." Where did I hear that recently?
到处都在说 连报新闻的都这么说
Everywhere. Even on the news women talk about cute butts.
不知是谁先起的头
It's really caught on.
那我的屁股呢？
So how's my butt?
-还不赖 -是吗？翘不翘？
- Not bad. - Is it cute though?
难说，要用量角器量吗？
Are we grading on a curve?
你多久前约会的？
When was your last date?
吉米·卡特总统时代，1978年
Jimmy Carter... 1978.
现在方式有点改变 首先你们先交朋友，彼此喜欢
Things are different now. First you have to be friends.
再亲吻 这阶段可以维持好几年
Then you neck. This could go on for years.
接着是验血戴保险套 但饭钱可以平分
Then you have tests and do it with a condom. But you do split the check.
-我不能让女人出饭钱 -全市市民会极度推崇你
- I can't let a woman pay. - They'll throw a parade for you.
你会是西雅图年度人物
You'll be Man of the Year.
-提拉米苏，你会知道 -那是什么的
Tira misu. You'll find out what that is.
若对方要我做 我不会怎么办？
Some woman will want me to do it to her, and I won't know what it is.
-包你爱死 -约会会很难
- You'll love it. - This is going to be tough.
何不约班家那设计师？ 她挺活泼的
What about that decorator? She's perky.
我还不敢开口 目前只是收集资料
No. I'm far away from that. I'm just making notes.
-我怎么开口？ -打电话说：“过来选颜色”
- How would I do it? - Ask her over to look at swatches.
-打电话说：“过来选颜色”？ -对，选颜色
- To look at swatches? - Yeah, color schemes.
别照念，用你自己的方法 想想加里·格兰特
Don't do it like I did. Be suave. Think Cary Grant.
加里·格兰特会说 “过来看我的颜色样本”吗？
Would he say, "Come look at my swatches"?
-不是在电影中… -在《Gunga Din》里？
- Not it in movies... - Not in Gunga Din?
那不是爱情电影 或许他在真实生活里说过
Gunga Din isn't that kind of film. Who knows what he did in real life.
跟戴安·佳能说？ 对呀“黛安，来看我的颜色样本”
- He did that with Dyan Cannon? - "Dyan, look at these swatches."
乔纳，我回来了
Jonah, I'm home!
乔纳？
Jonah?
乔纳
Jonah.
爸，这是杰西卡
Hi, Dad. This is Jessica.
很高兴见到你，杰西卡
Nice to meet you.
好有趣 倒放时，是“保罗死了”
This is amazing. If you play this backwards, it says "Paul is dead."
-我知道 -你怎么知道？
- Yeah, I know. - How do you know?
-爸，门关一下 -好
- Dad, could you shut the door? - Sure.
H和G 嗨和再见
H and G. Hi and goodbye.
?Gene Autry: "Back in the Saddle Again"?
?I'm back in the saddle again ?
喂，维多莉亚吗？
Hello, Victoria?
我是山姆·鲍德温，记得吗？
This is Sam Baldwin. I don't know if you remember me...
太好了
Oh, great.
我在想 你是否愿意和我喝一杯
I was wondering if you would like to have a drink with me?
晚餐？
Dinner?
那更好…
Dinner would be even better.
周五可以…
Friday would be great.
听说那地方不错
I hear that's a good place.
七点半很好，我…
Seven-thirty is fine. And I'll...
好，到时见
Okay, I'll meet you there.
决定周五 七点半吃晚饭，好极了
So it's Friday at 7:30 for dinner. Great.
我也是，再见
Me too. Bye.
?Back in the saddle again ?
-你爱他吗？ -现在不爱了
- Are you in love with him?  - Not now.
-那时的人才懂得爱 -你疯了
- Those people knew how to love. - You're a basket case.
时空都无法使他们分离 因为他们知道
They knew it. Nothing could separate them because they knew.
-那是真实正确的 -这是电影
- It was real. - It's a movie.
你的毛病就出在这里，你不想恋爱 你想要电影中的恋爱，念给我听
You don't want to be in love, you want to be in a movie. Read it.
“夜未眠父子： 我从没写过这种信”
"Dear Sleepless and Son. I've never written a letter like this before."
-每个人都这么写 -我知道，你当我白痴？
- That's what everyone writes. - You think I don't know that?
华特怎么办？
What about Walter?
华特，我一心想嫁华特
I'd give anything to marry Walter.
他完全无法预料 你以为你看得穿他，其实不行
He's so unexpected. You think you know him, but you don't.
我该写些关于魔力的事
I should write about magic.
若我命中属于他 却无缘相识
What if this man is my destiny, and I never meet him?
-有缘不一定好 -“我想见你们”
- Your destiny can be your doom. - "I want to meet you"...
-在帝国大厦顶楼 -在帝国大厦顶楼
- On the Empire State Building. - On the Empire State Building.
情人节日落时
Sunset, Valentine's Day.
我那时和华特在纽约 可以抽空出现
I'll be in New York with Walter. I can squeeze it in.
我将和华特在纽约
I'll be in New York with Walter!
因为命运我嫁给了马丁 买了有棵死树的房子
Because of fate I married Martin and bought the house with the dead tree.
所以离婚了
On account of which I got divorced and hit a car...
还害我撞车遇上瑞克
...and met Rick, while buying a neck brace.
等等，你没有提过 你离婚是因为死树
You got divorced because of a tree?
-是园丁 -你爱上园丁？
- The tree man. - You fell in love with him?
我没说爱，我有说吗？ 我最爱看这段
I did not say love. This is my favorite part.
-现在或者永无机会 -永无是个可怕的字眼
- It's now or never. - Never is a frightening word.
错过幸福，我们就是傻子
We'd be fools to let happiness pass us by.
没有温暖回忆的 冬季多冷啊
Winter must be cold for those with no warm memories.
我们已错过春天
We've already missed the spring.
-男人就是看不懂这部戏 -我知道
- Men never get this movie. - I know.
妈咪！妈咪！
Mummy! Mummy!
-妈咪！ -别怕，我在这儿
- Mummy! - It's okay. I'm here. I'm coming.
没事了，梦到什么？
It's okay. What was that about?
房子在下沉，水从窗子灌进来
Our house was sinking. There was water coming in all the windows.
现在没事了
Well, it's okay now.
现在怎么办？你做噩梦时 你妈都唱歌给你听
What shall we do? Your mother sang to you when you had bad dreams.
唱“再见，黑鸟”
"Bye Bye Blackbird."
我想她 人死后会怎样？
I miss her. What happens to someone after they die?
-我不知道 -你相信有天堂吗？
- I don't know. - Do you believe in heaven?
从不信还有来生 但现在不确定了
I never believed in an afterlife. But now, I don't know.
因为我梦到… 你妈
Because I've had these dreams about your mum.
我们谈了很久 谈你的情况
We have long talks... about you.
她好像都知道 但我还是告诉她了
How you're doing. She sort of knows, but I tell her anyway.
那怎么解释？ 有点像来生吧？
So what is that? It's sort of an afterlife, isn't it?
我开始忘记她了
I'm starting to forget her.
她会削苹果
She could peel an apple...
皮都不断
...in one long, curly strip.
?Joe Cocker: "Bye Bye Blackbird"?
整个苹果
The whole apple.
?Pack up all my cares and woes ?
?Feeling low ?
?Here I go ?
?I said bye ?
?Bye ?
-我爱你，乔纳 -我爱你，爸
- I love you, Jonah.  - I love you, Dad.
?Where somebody waits for me ?
明天见
See you tomorrow.
?Sugar sweet so is she ?
?Bye ?
?I said bye ?
?Blackbird ?
?No one seems to love ?
?Or understand me ?
?And all the hard luck stories ?
?They keep handing me ?
?Where somebody shines the light ?
?I'm be coming on home tonight ?
?Bye, bye ?
?I wanna say ?
?Blackbird ?
?Lord have mercy ?
?Wait for me darling, yeah ?
劳莉吗？我是安妮 我很好
Laurie? It's Annie. I'm fine.
我在做电台直播节目专访 你认识菲尔斯通医生的工作人员吗？
I'm writing about radio shows. Do you know Dr. Fieldstone?
我是记者，我在写人们 如何处理悲痛专稿
I work for the Baltimore Sun, and I'm doing a piece on bereavement.
听说西雅图有位听众…
I understand you had a caller from Seattle.
我是乔纳·鲍德温 我们不在…
This is Jonah Baldwin. We're not in right now...
（输入您的需求）
（第216位鲍德温 请输入资料）
（寻找山姆，乔纳·鲍德温）
（寻获）
（玛格丽特·鲍德温死亡 山姆之爱妻，乔纳之母）
（葬礼与1991年6月10日 星期四10点举行）
建筑师
Architect.
（山姆·鲍德温，城市建筑师）
(AAA侦探社 华盛顿西雅图）
（基本资料，附照片）
（山姆·鲍德温，西雅图建筑师）
（资料保密）
我可能凌晨回来 如果失败八点半就会回来
I'll be back either by midnight or 8:30, if disaster strikes.
-这是寄给我俩的 -“夜未眠父子，巴尔的摩”
- Here's one for both of us. - "Sleepless and Son, Baltimore."
小儿科医生的电话在这里
Here's the doctor's number.
如误饮毒剂，这有瓶吐剂
Here's a bottle of Ipecac if anybody drinks poison.
-我这身如何？可以吗？ -很棒
How do I look? Do I look all right?
我一副急于讨好的蠢样 该去理个发
I look stupid. I'm trying too hard. I was going to get a haircut.
-这封信很好 -鞋跟的形状好奇怪
- This is a good letter, Dad. - These heels are grotesque.
她叫安妮·瑞德
Her name is Annie Reed.
爸，你看嘛
Dad, read this.
“夜未眠父子…
"Dear Sleepless and Son...
我是杰出三垒手 说到这个
I'm an excellent third baseman, and let me tell you...
罗宾斯是最棒的三垒手 我是老乡当然无异议”
...Robinson was the best. We must agree on this. I'm from Baltimore."
她跟你一样喜欢罗宾斯 这是个好预兆
She likes Brooks Robinson. So do you. It's a sign.
过来，我教你什么叫预兆
Come here. I'll show you a sign.
西雅图在哪？ 对，巴尔的摩呢？这边
Where's Seattle? And Baltimore? Right there!
中间隔26州，这是啥预兆？
There's like 26 states between here and there. That's a sign.
我走了，晚安，我爱你
I'm out of here. Goodbye. I love you.
克莉斯，你车移开了吗？
Clarise, did you move your car?
-谢谢，我要… -白酒？
- Thanks, Derrick. I'll have... - White wine spritzer?
-你呢？ -不用
- And you, sir? - I'm fine.
-你很漂亮 -你也很英俊
- You look good. - So do you.
我以为你永远不会打给我
I thought you'd never call me.
我好希望你会
I really wanted you to.
鲍德温先生，你的电话
Mr. Baldwin, phone call for you.
-爸，我们情人节去纽约好吗？ -什么？
Dad, can we go to New York for Valentine's Day?
安妮约我们情人节在 帝国大厦顶楼见
Annie Reed wants to meet us at the top of the Empire State Building.
乔纳，你跌倒流血了吗？ 克莉斯被勒死了吗？
Jonah, have you fallen down? Has Clarise been strangled?
-没有啊 -你就为了问这事？
- No. - Is that the reason you're calling?
现在订机票比较便宜 杰西卡父母开旅行社
We can get cheap tickets from Jessica's parents.
现在没空 以后再说
We'll talk about it later.
根本不该和你聊 去睡觉
This conversation has lasted too long. Go to bed.
-没问题吧？ -你有孩子吗？
- Everything all right? - Yes. Do you have kids?
我的送你好吗？
You want mine?
我喝纯伏特加
I'll have an Absolut straight up.
放下，别玩
Put that down. Stop it!
-她来了 -她干嘛买菜？
- There she is. - Why is she bringing groceries?
-她要做菜给我们吃 -嗨！山姆，谢谢
- She's going to cook for us. - Hi, Sam.
我猜你一定是乔纳
Let me guess. You must be Jonah.
就这些吗？ 车子在那边
This is it? The car is this way.
她重漆六次 现在她又要重做火炉
She's on her sixth painter. And now she wants the fireplace rebricked.
-我跟她很熟，我去劝她 -我有办法，用砖敲她
- I know her. I could call her. - I'll just hit her with a brick.
好好笑，你好风趣
That's so funny. You're so funny.
每次她想改装就说 “我很笨，你是专家
When she wants something done she says: "You know best.
但房子前后 能否颠倒过来？
But couldn't we flip the house so the back is in front?
前门上绞链 以便遥控开车库门”
Put the front on a hinge so I can get in with a garage door opener."
-“我说可以，只要…” -“把橱柜移开”
- "Yes, we can. We'll just..." - "Move the cabinets."
乔纳，点心拿过来
Jonah, bring some of that stuff.
你喜欢棒球吗？
Do you like baseball?
喜欢，我公司有水手队的包厢 不如大家去看一场
Yes. In fact my firm has box seats to the Mariners. Let's go some day.
露营呢？你喜欢吗？
What about camping? Do you like that?
我去露营过一次
I went camping once.
-爸，我们应该常去露营 -对，露营很好，睡觉了
- We should go camping more often. - You're right. Time for bed.
-才十点 -对，该睡了
- It's only 10:00. - That's right. Time for bed.
晚安
Goodnight.
不谢谢 维多莉亚做的好菜吗？
Thank Victoria for the nice dinner.
谢谢你的晚餐 我从没看过有人这么煮土豆
Thanks for dinner. I never saw anybody cook potatoes that way.
你喜欢就好，晚安
I'm glad you liked it. Goodnight, Jonah.
我们很少吃土豆 我们吃米
We don't see a lot of potatoes here. We're rice men.
抱歉，华特
I'm sorry, Walter. I'm sorry.
打开收音机
Turn on your radio.
又是那小鬼 你害我听这烂节目
The kid is on. You've got me listening to this garbage!
是贝琪，她又跟瑞克吵架 贝琪，我再打过去
Becky's having trouble with Rick. Becky, I'll call you back.
对不起，华特 流血了吗？
I'm sorry, Walter. Are you bleeding?
他正在亲她
He's kissing her right now!
乔纳，你在监视你父亲
Are you spying on your father?
-他在亲谁？ -我要阻止他们
- Who is he kissing? - I have to make them stop.
-叫我怎么向华特解释？ -她做晚餐
- How will I explain this to Walter? - She made dinner.
她买了两大包的菜 可以吃一年了
She brought food for a whole year!
你父亲约会那很好呀 你只是受不了
It's good that your father's dating. It's just hard on you.
事情真如你所愿时 你吓坏了
You think you want it, but when it happens, it scares you.
合不合适该由你爸决定
Shouldn't your father decide whether someone is right for him?
他现在神智不清
He's not sane enough.
他在吻她的唇 她是烂货，我爸被烂货勾引
He's kissing her on the lips. My dad's been captured by a 'ho!
冷静点 明早吃早餐时
Calm down. Tomorrow, when you're having breakfast...
再和你父亲谈 别闷在心里
...tell him how you feel. Don't keep it inside.
拿着收音机 躲在清洁柜里
Miss Scarlett. In the broom closet. With the radio.
华特，你吓死我了，下次不准这样
Walter, you scared me. Don't ever do that again.
-我以为有只黑寡妇蜘蛛 -你把我和维多莉亚吓个半死
- I saw a black widow. - You scared me and Victoria.
-本来在那里啊 -下次再看到黑寡妇就说
- It was right there. - Next time I want you to say:
“爸，打扰了 我看到有毒昆虫”
"Dad, I see a poisonous insect."
我就会来，别再大叫了
And I'll deal with it. Don't scream.
贝琪以为电台 有个人是瑞克
Becky thought Rick was on the radio.
结果是个住德鲁市的人 德鲁在哪？
It turned out the guy lived in Duluth. Where's Duluth?
-这没道理 -我知道毫无道理
- That doesn't make any sense. - I know. No sense at all.
-感谢主我生活有序 -德鲁在北达科他州
- Thank God my life is in place. - Duluth? That's in North Dakota.
-我喜欢这封信，你该回信 -你觉得吗？
- Great letter. Write to her. - You think so?
是YOH 你唯一的希望
It's Y-O-H. Your only hope.
我要写电台节目报导
I thought I'd do a story on those radio shows.
-也许还要实地研究 -没错
- You'd have to go somewhere. - Definitely.
-不能电话采访吗？ -这篇不行
- Can't you do a phone interview? - No.
-我不会在芝加哥待太久 -你回来时我已经走了
- I won't be in Chicago long. - When you get back, I'll be gone.
-那就纽约见 -我来开
- Then I'll see you in New York. - I'll get it.
我是布朗宁机长 高度三万五千英尺
This is Captain Browning. We're cruising at 35,000 feet.
天气晴朗 可望准时飞抵西雅图
The weather is clear and we'll be in Seattle on schedule.
-你讨厌飞行吗？ -对，我刚向我要嫁的人撒了大谎
- Don't you hate flying? - Yes, and I've told a terrible lie.
你觉得这是不是 一种背叛？
Is any lie a betrayal?
我是在说飞行
I said flying.
-谢谢你送我来 -他喜欢飞机
- Thanks for bringing me here. - He likes the planes.
回来送你个纪念品 雪球好吗？摇一摇雪花就飘落
Can I bring you back a souvenir? Maybe one of these snow globes?
我很喜欢，谢谢
Sure, I'd really like that. Thank you so much.
-他才八岁 -他很厉害
- He's eight. - He's good at it.
报导说八岁的孩子都这样 是很正常的
I've read an article about it. Children are hideous at that age.
等我回来后 或许我俩可以单独聚聚，如何？
Maybe when I come back, the two of us ought to spend some time alone.
-再见，再见，乔纳 -再见
Bye. Bye, Jonah.
乔纳
Jonah.
听着，你不了解维多莉亚
Listen, you don't know Victoria.
我也不了解 对我来说她是个谜
In fact she's a mystery to me too.
她常甩头发，为什么？
She tosses her hair a lot. Why?
抽筋还是该剪头发？ 她该用发夹夹住对吗？
Is it a twitch? Does she need a haircut or a barrette?
我想搞清楚这些事 所以才会跟她约会
I'd like to understand these things. And that's why I'm dating her.
约会而已 不是同居或娶她
Just dating. I'm not living with her. I'm not marrying her.
你能了解这差别吗？
Can you appreciate the difference?
单身贵族都这么做 先尝试彼此是否适应
That's what single people do. They see how other people fit.
互相调整，没有人完美无缺 根本没完美这回事
Everyone's an adjustment. There's no such thing as a perfect...
走吧
Come on.
爸，我和杰西卡谈到未来 她说你和安妮在前世认识
Dad, Jessica says you knew Annie in another life.
写信那个 你们上辈子没有在一起
The one who wrote us. But you never got together in that life.
就像缺角的拼图 两人在一起才完整
Your hearts will be a complete puzzle once you're together.
我年幼纯洁 所以我比较能接触宇宙力量
I know that because I'm young and pure, in touch with cosmic forces.
谁告诉你这些的？ 我郑重劝你别娶杰西卡
Who told you that? I sure hope you're not marrying Jessica.
?Harry Connick Jr.: "A Wink and a Smile"?
?I remember the days ?
?Of just keeping time ?
?Of hanging around ?
?In sleepy towns forever ?
?Back roads empty for miles ?
?Well, you can't have a dream ?
?And cut it to fit ?
?But when I saw you, I knew ?
?We'd go together ?
?Like a wink and a smile ?
?Leave your old jalopy ?
?By the railroad track ?
?We'll get a hip double-dip tip-toppy ?
?Two-seat Pontiac ?
?So you can rev her up ?
?Don't go slow ?
?It's only green lights and all rights ?
?Let's go together ?
?With a wink and a smile ?
?Give me a wink and a smile ?
?We go together ?
?Like a wink and a smile ?
?Now my heart is music ?
?Such a simple song ?
?Sing it again ?
?The notes never end ?
?This is where I belong ?
?Just the sound of your voice ?
?The light in your eyes ?
?We're so far away from yesterday ?
?Together with a wink and a smile ?
?We go together ?
?Like a wink and a smile ?
-我看着他陪他儿子在海边玩 -跟他讲话没有？
- I watched them play at the beach.  - Did you talk to him?
我不敢
Couldn't do it.
-我怎么来的？ -你撒了个谎搭上飞机
- How did I get here? - You lied and got on a plane.
-我明天去找他谈 -好，再见
- I'm going to talk to him tomorrow. - Okay. Good. Goodbye.
贝琪
Beck.
-这么做是不是很疯狂？ -不，这就是奇妙之处
- Is this crazy? - No, that's the weirdest part.
-谢谢，我爱你 -我也爱你
- Thank you. I love you. - I love you too.
见到你真开心 葛瑞格在哪里？
It's good to see you. Where's Greg?
你好
Hello.
-然后呢？ -我就走了
- Then what? - I left, obviously.
-你站在路中央？ -记得梦到自己赤裸？
- You were in the street? - It was like walking around naked.
-我喜欢这个梦 -也比不上我的这么丢人
- I love that dream. - This was more humiliating.
他看到你了？面对面？
But he saw you. You were face to face.
他说“你好” 我只说得出“你好”
He said hello. And all I could say was hello.
-我只说得出“你好” -这是个好预兆
- All I could say was hello. - It's a sign.
表示我这部片看太多遍了
It's a sign that I've watched this movie too many times.
我好笨！听到广播后 我就像个蠢蛋
From the minute I heard that program I've been a complete jerk.
-你不是蠢蛋 -谢谢，白痴好了
- You're not a jerk. - Thank you. An idiot!
-你又不知道她是谁 -我有她的照片
- You don't know who she was. - I have a picture of her.
你看，西雅图的侦探社给我的 在这里，一模一样
The detective sent it to me. See, that's what she looks like.
-这是张背影 -是她，而他迷恋她
- It's her back. - It's her and he's crazy about her.
这是什么？ 西雅图寄来的
What's this? It's from Seattle.
贝琪
Becky.
我替你把信寄了
So I mailed your letter.
“亲爱的安妮 谢谢你的来信，你似乎很正点”
"Dear Annie. Thanks for your letter. You sound neat.
“我们很高兴情人节与你见面 并看看是否…”
We're excited about meeting you in New York and seeing if we are...
“MFEO”
...M-F-E-O.
“再见 西雅图夜未眠”
See you soon. Sleepless in Seattle."
MFEO？
M-F-E-O?
是彼此合适
Made for each other.
蛮俏皮的
It's cute. Like a little clue.
他文笔奇差，无所谓啦
So he can't write. Big deal.
语文能力被过分重视 多要求是自寻苦恼
Verbal ability is overrated in guys. Our need for it leads to trouble.
-我要回去找华特 -那这封信呢？
- I'm going to run back to Walter. - And the letter?
信是之前写的 是认识那女人前写的
It was written before I went out there. Before the 'ho.
问题是她看来不像个坏女人 倒像是个亲切的朋友
But she didn't look like a 'ho. She looked like one of our friends.
-你在机场看到她的？ -仿佛我早就认识她，奇怪
- You saw her in the airport too? - It was like I knew her.
-像似曾相识？ -非常法式似曾相识的情节
- Like a d茅j脿-vu? - It was very d茅j脿-vu-ish.
-至少你开始约会了 -就这么一个
- At least you're seeing people. - Well, only one.
-维多莉亚 -你不喜欢她？
- Victoria. - You don't like her?
-她笑起来像土狼 -是吗？
- She laughs like a hyena. - Is this true?
没有…有一点 说出你干的好事
Sort of. Tell them what you did.
电台的事，说呀
Tell them about the radio show.
平安夜那天 他打电话给电台
Christmas Eve he calls a radio show.
-说我需要新老婆 -真的？好感人
- And tells them I need a new wife. - That's so sweet.
现在又有一个 迷人的女人来信
Now he's obsessed with a woman who wrote me.
她约我在帝国大厦顶楼见面
She wants to meet me on top of Empire State.
在情人节时
On Valentines Day.
就像那部电影《An Affair to Remember》没看过吗？
It's like that movie. An Affair to Remember.
加里·格兰特和黛博拉·范儿 是儿还是尔？
Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr. Is that "car" or "cur"?
他们约好在帝国大厦 顶楼见面，但她被车撞了
They were to meet at the Empire State, but she got hit by a taxi.
他等了又等 那天下着雨
He waited and waited. And it was raining.
结果… 她太好强，不想让他知道自己…
Then she's too proud to tell him that she's...
跛了，他也倔强地 不肯找出她不来的原因
...crippled. And he's too proud to find out why she doesn't come.
但他还是去找她
But he comes to see her anyway.
他去找她时…
It's amazing when he visits her.
没注意她未起身寒暄
He doesn't notice that she doesn't get up to say hello.
他句句讽刺
And he's very bitter.
当他准备走掉 不知道她为何…
You think he's going to walk out and never know why.
一直盖着毯子蜷在沙发上
She's just lying there with a blanket over her shrivelled legs.
-你还好吧？ -她没事
- Are you all right? - She's fine.
他突然说…我看到画了 他走到卧房
Then he says, "I saw the painting," and goes into the bedroom.
看一眼，出来，再看着她
And he comes out and looks at her.
他发现了，两人相拥
And they just know and hug and it's so...
-那是女人看的电影 -对啊
- That's a chick's movie. - I'd say so.
-谁会听听广播就写信来？ -有好几百封呢
- Who'd write a guy from the radio? - I got hundreds of letters.
-饥不择食 -要个好男人，怎算是饥不择食？
- Desperate women. - Is wanting a nice guy desperate?
超过四十岁要结婚 比被恐怖份子杀死的机率还低…
It's easier to be killed by terrorists than to marry over 40.
-胡说八道 -是，甜心
- That is not true! - Right, honey.
我不要邮寄新娘 我只想找个人
I don't want a mail-order bride. Just someone who can converse...
可以边吃饭边聊 不会因电影而大哭
...without falling into weepy tears over an old movie.
看《The Dirty Dozen》结尾时我有哭 吉米·布朗丢手榴弹
I cried over The Dirty Dozen. Jim Brown throwing the grenades.
理查德·杰柯和李·马文 乔扮纳粹
Richard Jaeckel and Lee Marvin on top of a tank dressed like Nazis.
他们等着特里尼·洛佩兹 在跳伞时折断颈子
Trini Lopez... breaks his neck when they're parachuting.
理查德·杰柯是宪兵 戴了钢盔
Richard Jaeckel had on a shiny helmet, because he was an MP.
别再说了 我爱死那部电影
Please, no more. God, I love that movie.
-这是我看过最棒的电影 -好在哪里？
- This is the best movie I ever saw. - What's so great about it?
-你一定得找到她，乔纳 -你知道去纽约要多少钱吗？
- You have to find her. - How much would it cost to go?
谁晓得，票价天天变
Nobody knows. It changes practically every day.
-你有多少钱？ -80元
- How much money do you have? - 80 dollars.
-我有42，计程车费可能够了 -可是我怎么去呢？
- I have 42. That'll cover cabs. - How would I get there?
-我得去送票，你看一下家好吗？ -好，妈
I have to drop these tickets off. Can you keep an eye on things?
(1993年2月14日 联合航空，航班号597)
（纽约机场）
（乔纳·鱼包德温）
-靠窗还是走道？ -靠窗
- Window seat or aisle? - Window.
要水果盘吗？ 我从不吃机上的食物
You want a fruit plate? I'd rather die than eat airplane food.
我说你十二岁 才可单独飞行
I'll write you're 12. That way you can fly unaccompanied.
-神经病！谁会相信？ -进了电脑，他们就会信
- Who'd believe I'm 12? - They'll believe the computer.
我说你太矮 这样说你不会生气吧？
I'll say you're short for your age, but that they shouldn't mention it.
好主意
Great idea!
?Tammy Wynette: "Stand by Your Man"?
?Sometimes it's hard to be a woman ?
?Giving all your love to just one man ?
-火车快开了 -不会赶不上
- You'll miss the train.  - No I won't.
我好快乐，我终于快乐了 这才是正确真实
I'm so happy, Becky. This is right. It's real.
其余只是看太多电影
The other things happen in movies.
别跟别人说 我迷恋想像中的人
Don't tell anyone what I did. I'd die...
那影响我的专业形象，保证？
...if anyone knew I did anything like that. You promise?
西雅图夜未眠已成历史
Sleepless in Seattle is history.
?... hard to understand ?
?And if you love him ?
?Oh, be proud of him ?
?'Cause after all he's just a man ?
?Stand by your man ?
-说吧 -你先说
- Go ahead. - No, you go.
我要说，自从圣诞节后
I was going to say that since Christmas...
你变得有点分心
...you've been kind of distracted.
但现在 你好像又回头了
But now it feels as if you're coming back from wherever you were.
是的
I am.
我只是…我有点… 我想我有点紧张
I was just... I think I got nervous.
但那是正常的吧？ 你不紧张吗？关于…你知道的
But that's normal, right? Don't you ever feel nervous...
-什么？ -永远在一起
- About what? - Forever.
不紧张
No.
我会…
Well... I did.
你知道我怎么想吗？ 我觉得有点太完美了
And I think I thought it was too perfect.
我怕正正得负
I was afraid we'd be two rights making a wrong.
好像是命运，其实不然 你知道我的意思吧
You know, it was like kismet, but not, if you see what I mean.
你得成长，却不能 保有对生命的憧景
You have to grow up and forget the adolescent fantasies about...
别怪我，我喜欢这花色
...how exciting life will be. I'm sorry, but I love this pattern.
不会吧？ 这和我祖母的瓷器一模一样
You couldn't. This is just like my grandmother's china.
-要几组？ -十组
- How many place settings? - Ten.
八组太少，十二组… 太多
Exactly. Eight is too few, twelve is too many.
-华特 -这是我妈的
- Walter. - It was my mother's.
我送去缩小尺寸 她的手指好肥
I had them size it down. She had really fat fingers.
好漂亮，若是我…
It's so beautiful. It's exactly what I'd pick...
也会选这一只
...if I had every ring in the world to choose from.
懂吗？有些人希望 感情充满惊喜
Some people want a relationship to be full of surprises...
但我绝对不是
...but I'm not one of them.
惊喜已被高估
Surprises are highly overrated.
我早上出发，只过一夜 克莉斯会来
I'll only be gone one night. Clarise will be here.
你可以看恐怖电影
You can watch scary movies.
-你和她一起去吗？ -我和维多莉亚一起去，对
- Are you going with her? - I'm going with Victoria.
别耍花招
Don't try anything tricky.
不准碰毒蔓藤 把自己关起来或碰伤
Don't roll in poison ivy or do anything so you need stitches.
手指断了就断了 没人会送你上医院做雷射手术
If your finger falls off, it stays off. I won't take you to hospital.
-是因为巴尔的摩那女人吗？ -安妮
- Is this about that woman? - Annie.
-我才不管你 -我来告诉你我要做什么
- I don't care what you do! - I'll tell you what I'm doing.
我要上床 我是唯一一个在90年代上床的人
I'm getting laid. I'm the only man in the 90s who's getting laid.
我多久没上过床了 大学交过六，七个女孩
And I haven't been laid that much. Six or seven girls at college.
你站多久了？ 听到我说的话没？
How long have you been there? What did you hear me say?
-大学交过六，七个 -七，不，八个，玛丽·凯利
- "Six or seven girls at college." - Seven. Eight! Mary Kelly.
我喜欢这个
This is the one I like.
乔纳，你不会喜欢任何女人 因为她不是你妈
Jonah, you won't like any woman, because it isn't your mother.
-你哪知道？安妮哪里不好？ -乔纳，闭嘴！
- What's wrong with Annie? - Jonah, shut up.
闭嘴？ 妈从不说闭嘴或对我吼
Shut up? Mum never told me to shut up or yelled at me.
-我不跟你说了 -我们为何不能去纽约？
This conversation is over!
那个女人可能是疯子 你没看《Fatal Attraction》吗？
This woman could be a sick lunatic. Didn't you see Fatal Attraction?
-你不准我看 -我看了！吓死美国所有男人
- You wouldn't let me. - It scared every man in America.
你不答应我就不走开
I'm not leaving till you say yes.
我恨你…！
I hate you!
好，你再去电台说 你爸爸如何毁了你的人生
Good, then you can tell Oprah how your dad ruined your life...
只因为他想上酒店开房
...by going off for a weekend special at the Holiday Inn!
乔纳，克莉斯来了 我要走了
Jonah, Clarise is here and I've got to go.
乔纳，我要走了
Jonah, listen, I've got to go.
杰西卡，你一定要说出他在哪 乔纳的父亲很着急
Jessica, tell us where he is. Jonah's dad is very upset.
杰西卡，我是你爸 告诉我们他在哪
Jessica, this is your father. Tell us where he is.
-NY -意思是不可能
- N-Y. - That means "no way."
那是NW！
That's N-W!
-纽约，他去纽约了 -怎么去的？
- He's on his way to New York. - How?
联合597班机
United, 597.
-几点起飞？ -七点半
- When does it leave? - Seven thirty.
送你个别针做纪念
Here's a pin for flying with us.
-背包我帮你拿 -不用了
- Can I take this for you? - No.
-去哪，孩子？ -帝国大厦
- Where to, kid? - Empire State Building.
-帝国大厦 -别靠人行道那么近
- Empire State Building. - Don't stop so close to the curb.
到了 上去干嘛？吐口水？
There it is. What are you going to do up there? Spit off the top?
不，我要去见我的新妈妈
No, I'm meeting my new mother.
（帝国大厦）
-抱歉，我是乔纳，你是安妮吗？ -不，我叫辛西亚
- I'm Jonah. Are you Annie? - No, I'm Cynthia.
抱歉，你是安妮吗？
Excuse me, are you Annie?
位子很好，多谢
Great table. Thanks.
怎么了？
Is something wrong?
-喝点什么吗？ -香槟？
- Can I get you a drink? - Champagne?
好
Fine.
来一瓶唐·德路易斯
We'll have a bottle of Dom DeLuise.
-开玩笑的 -他是说唐·培里侬香槟王
- Just kidding. - He meant Dom Perignon.
好美
Beautiful view.
华特，我要告诉你一件事
Walter. There's something I must tell you.
抱歉，急事
Sorry, an emergency.
钱！看到没？
Money, money, money, see?
他现在应该已在 帝国大厦的顶楼
So he could be on top of the Empire State Building now?
不，应该不会
No. I guess he could be. No.
华特，问题不在他，而在我 不能嫁你
It's not him, Walter. It's me. I can't do this.
安妮，我爱你 但我们就到此为止
Annie, I love you. But let's leave that out of this.
我不要成为将就的对象
I don't want to be someone that you or anybody else settles for.
姻缘路本来就够艰苦了
Marriage is hard enough without such low expectations.
-不是吗？ -华特，我配不上你
- Isn't it? - Walter, I don't deserve you.
别这么说
No, I wouldn't put it that way.
不过，这样说也好
But okay.
-你还好吧？ -还好
- You okay? - Yeah.
-什么？ -你看
- What? - Look.
-那是个预兆 -谁需要什么预兆？
- It's a sign. - Who needed a sign?
华特，我非去不可
Walter, I have to go.
乔纳…
Jonah!
爸
Dad!
你若出事怎么办？ 我若找不到你怎么办？
What if something happened to you? What if I couldn't get to you?
对不起…
I'm sorry.
你叫我怎么办？ 你是我唯一的亲人
What would I have done? You're my family. You're all I have.
我以为她会来
I thought she'd be here.
我们父子很和睦吧？ 我做过什么蠢事没？
We're doing okay, right? So far, have I done anything stupid?
-我让我们感情破裂没？ -没有
- Have I screwed it up for us? - No.
（帝国大厦）
-观景台 -抱歉，现在来晚了
- Observation deck? - Sorry, it's too late.
-不，我非上去不可 -我们要关门了
- Please. I need to get up there. - We're closing up.
我看一下就好，我约了人
Can I just take a look? I'm supposed to meet someone.
他也许没来 但我不去看不会死心
He's probably not there, but if I don't look, I'll always wonder.
-加里·格兰特，对吧？ -你知道那部电影？
- Cary Grant, right? - You know that movie?
我太太最爱看了
It's one of my wife's favorites.
或许回家后我们养条狗
Maybe when we get home we'll get a dog.
-你不喜欢狗吗？ -喜欢啊
- Wouldn't you like to have a dog? - Sure.
抱歉，女士，没有人
I'm sorry, ma'am. Empty.
-我可以转一圈吗？ -请便
- Can I take a minute? - Go ahead.
我忘在望远镜旁边
I left it by the telescopes.
是你，我在街上看到过你
It's you. I saw you in the street.
-你是安妮吗？ -是的
- Are you Annie? - Yes.
你就是安妮？
You're Annie?
-这一定是你的 -我叫乔纳
- This must be yours. - I'm Jonah.
-这是我爸爸，他叫山姆 -嗨，乔纳
- This is my dad. His name is Sam. - Hi, Jonah.
山姆
Sam.
-这位呢？ -霍华德
- And who's this? - Howard.
我们走吧
We'd better go.
好吗？
Shall we?
?Jimmy Durante: "Make Someone Happy"?
?It's so important ?
?To make someone happy ?
?Make just one someone happy ?
?Make just one heart to heart you ?
?You sing to ?
山姆，很高兴认识你
Sam, it's nice to meet you.
?One face that lights ?
?When it nears you ?
?One girl you're ?
?You're everything to ?
?Fail if you win it ?
?Comes and goes in a minute ?
?Where's the real stuff in life ?
?To cling to ?
?Love is the answer ?
?Someone to love is the answer ?
?Once you've found her ?
?Build your world around her ?
?Make someone happy ?
?Make just one someone happy ?
?And you will be happy too ?
?Celine Dion & Clive Griffin: "When I Fall in Love"
?When I fall in love ?
?It will be forever ?
?Or I'll never fall in love ?
?I'll never, never fall in love ?
?In a restless world ?
?Like this is ?
?Love is ended before it's begun ?
?And too many ?
?Moonlight kisses ?
?Seem to cool ?
?In the warmth of the sun ?
?When I give my heart ?
?It will be completely ?
?Or I'll never give my heart ?
?And the moment I can feel ?
?That you feel that way too ?
?Is when I fall in love ?
?When I fall in love ?
?With you ?
?Louis Armstrong: "A Kiss to Build a Dream on"
?Give me a kiss ?
?To build on and my imagination ?
?Will thrive upon that kiss ?
?Sweetheart I ask no more than this, ?
?A kiss to build a dream on ?
?Give me a kiss ?
?Before you leave me ?
?And my imagination ?
?Will feed my hungry heart ?
?Leave me one thing before we part ?
?A kiss to build a dream on ?